You see her walking down the street
with her long black hair.
She looks away once more,
the men on the street won't let her by.
Oh, my girl, may you stay safe from the evil eye.
The stars are there to guide you,
may the wind take you wherever you want to go.
Oh, girl, I'm sending you the little angels.
I pray to heaven. I pray, I pray. (Girl.)
I'm sending you little angels.
I ask the heavens, I pray, I pray.
There is a mirror in my mother's house that I'm afraid to use.
It knows how vulnerable I am, I can't bear it.
I always used to speak to it and I ask for advice.
It knows how much I cried over a man I didn't know.
And when the day came, I looked into its eyes and saw something familiar.
His rose-like mouth, Cupid's bow and a lethal beauty.
Father, it's been a long time since I've seen you.
(A long time since I've seen you.)
Today my eyes fully recognize you.
(Fully recognize you.)
Father, it's been a long time since I've seen you.
(A long time since I've seen you.)
Today my eyes fully recognize you.
Tell me about your pains, your loves, your history.
About what you like to eat, about colors, and tell me more.
I want to know who you are when there's nobody watching.
I want you to hear this and know that you don't owe me anything.
And when the day came, I offered my hand and stopped searching.
Memories that he and I never had at a tender age.
Father, I haven't seen you in a long time.
(Haven't seen you in a long time.)
Today my eyes fully recognize you.
(Fully recognize you.)
Father, I haven't seen you in a long time.
(Haven't seen you in a long time.)
Today my eyes fully recognize you.
Back at my mom's house, I learned the truth.
I made peace with that very mirror.
Hi everyone.
Hi I'm YEИDRY.
This is our first time here in this office,
so we're a little nervous or maybe I should just speak for myself.
What else? The next one is one of my favorite songs.
OK, I'm not good at talking
One, two, three.
I ask for zeal, I sing to the heavens.
Two to the chest, we fly straight ahead.
I have a car, I have a roof, blessings that I deserve.
Lies, lies, lies.
I decide the truth.
I walk armored down the street, protected by my ancestors.
Ah, ah, nobody walks beside me.
I'll shut up whoever messes with me.
Lie, lie, lie.
I'm not asking for anything else.
I don't want to doubt anymore.
I almost fell into the trap.
I can't rest.
I want more from myself, and more and more.
I'm always looking for more.
If I keep going like this, that's it.
Like Icarus, I'm going to crash.
Lie, lie, lie.
I don't want anything else.
I don't want to hear it anymore.
Lie, lie, lie.
I always want more and more.
I'm not asking for anything else.
Short skirt, it doesn't matter,
cellulite, we all got it.
I've got swag.
Big ego.
Ready for what I deserve.
Lie, lie, lie.
This one for the baddies.
I prayed so hard to my saints for someone like you.
And now that I have you here, I realized this life isn't for me.
I told my eyes that if they were to cry for you,
it'd be for wanting to stay and not wanting to leave you.
Don't give me your heart, I don't even know how to take care of my own.
You trusted me with everything, baby, and I don't even trust myself.
And if I held you last night, it's not because I love you; I was just cold.
You gave me all of you, darling,
and I don't want you to be mine.
I'm sorry.
If I looked like I was in love.
Boy, my bad.
I got caught up.
This is a goodbye, like a stab in the heart.
I know you loved me, but I didn't promise you anything.
And I don't know why you planted a tree in the desert.
I was born this way. I'd say it's my fault, but that's not true.
My heart is deaf and you keep insisting on playing it a concert.
Understand me: Love didn't die; it was always dead.
Don't give me your heart. I don't even know how to take care of my own.
You trusted me with everything, baby, and I don't even trust myself.
And if I held you last night, it's not because I love you; I was just cold.
You gave me all of you, darling, and I don't want you to be mine.
This next song is — this next song is for all the ones that live far from their home.
From their family from their hearts, like me.
Like sand in the desert.
Like air in the lung.
Like light in the sky.
Like the dawn and its morning star.
That's how much I need you.
And even though sometimes I feel the weight. (Even though sometimes I feel it.)
And the pressure in my chest. (The pressure in my chest.)
Of loving, but being far away, of missing out on those memories.
And of being the older sister.
But when I wake up I'm still alone.
I count the hours to see you.
I think of you and the poppies.
I only think about going back.
Going back.
Every time I reach the front door of the house.
I feel like nothing has changed, everything is still the same.
Responsibility paired with nostalgia, it's wanting to stay and wanting to take flight.
They are my garden of dreams.
The smell of coffee and a hug upon waking.
Too much water in this sea.
They are my home. I can't change it.
But when I wake up I'm still alone, I count the hours until see you.
I think of you and the poppies.
I only think about going back.
Going back.
Going back, going back.
This sea that separates us has too much water in it for me.
And home is what I call the very place I once lost.
The sea that separates us has too much water in it for me.
I'm going to introduce the next song in Italian.
So my dad can understand me. Hi dad, I love you.
It's a song that I wrote for Italy.
To a place that welcomed me and that I love, where I grew up.
I don't live there anymore, so I miss it very much. And to my friends: Hi girls!
Wheat fields and concrete.
Wheat field and concrete welcomed me years ago.
I always believed it,
but dreaming at my age is expensive.
It's a rare pain.
And how many clouds will pass by before
I realize that I miss something about you.
There's a reason if we can't touch.
I left, but my heart stays with you.
There's no other way out, my heart stays with you.
OK. I always cry after that one so it was really hard.
What can I say?
I was born in Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic.
I grew up in Italy.
Today we're at Tiny Desk, which is pretty crazy.
The next song. Yes, I'm going to introduce it in Spanish.
It's called "No me vuelvo a enamorar" because I feel like we never forget our first love.
And for me, my first love was the Dominican Republic.
Helen and I are from there.
What's up!
Also, give it up for Helen.
Tiffany, Baird, Kiernan and Gelo.
Thank you guys for being here with me.
Well, it's Merenguito time.
I traveled roads that separate us.
But wherever I go, I see your face.
I've met others and they don't compare to you.
You will always be my clear-water beach.
You were my first love.
My favorite memory.
Whenever the sun comes up.
I close my eyes and return.
Without you, there is no flavor.
I search for it and can't find it.
That's why I come back to you, because after you, I won't fall in love again.
Quisqueya.
I won't fall in love again. (Quisqueya.)
I won't.
That sparkle in my eyes just thinking I'll see you again.
Sand between my toes and your sunrise in the background.
Coconut water for this thirst.
I sing with your rhythm and long for your love.
I'll never get used to the cold of this city.
The further away you are, the more scared I get.
I'm too Dominican to not start dancing when I hear your name from far away.
You were my first love, my favorite memory.
Whenever the sun rises, I close my eyes and return.
Without you there is no flavor.
I search for it and can't find it.
That's why I come back to you, because after you I'll never fall in love again.
Quisqueya.
I'll never fall in love again.
Never again.
I've got street flow, I put my people first.
And the moment I arrive, there's sancocho for everyone.
A little chair in the yard.
A speaker with dominoes, a party gets started in the DR, I know.
You were my first love, my favorite memory.
Whenever the sun rises, I close my eyes and return.
Without you there is no flavor. (I search for it and can't find it.)
That's why I come back to you.
Because after you, I'll never fall in love again.
Quisqueya.
Quisqueya, Quisqueya.
I'll never fall in love again.
There is no one else like you.
Thank you. Thank you.